Yeah, actually SQL is one of the most important basic skills that one should learn,
实际上 SQL是每个人都应该学习的一项基础技能
but it's not a very difficult language to learn.
而且它不是一门非常难学的语言
I think many people picked up the skill on the job,
我发现很多人因为工作才学习它
but it's definitely one of the most important skills to have.
但它本身就是一项很重要的技术
I can't think of a day in the past few years that I have not written a SQL query.
我几乎想不起来过去的几年中哪天我没写过 SQL 查询语句
How complex are those?
它们很复杂吗？
Are those are just like select from where so you have
它们仅仅是 select from  where 语句
giant subqueries that you run on a regular basis?
然后你就得到了一个可以定期执行的子查询语句
Do you think about efficiency when you write those?
你在写它们的时候是否考虑过效率问题
Yeah, It depends. I think when you're doing some ad hoc analysis,
是的 这要看情况而定 比如在要快速做一些数据分析的时候
you don't really care too much.
你不需要太过纠结
We just write a query that you need to answer your questions,
我们只要编写查询语句 回答你的问题即可
so it's more question-driven.
这是问题导向的任务
But there are times where you actually have to build out a ETL job,
不过 有时候你得搭建一个 ETL 管道
extract, transform, load, it's kind
提取 (extract) 转换(transform) 加载(load)
of the jargon that we use for building data pipelines.
这是我们搭建数据管道时使用的专业术语
When you're building out data pipelines,
在你搭建数据管道的时候
you need to be a little bit more careful and
需要更加仔细
then you need to be a little bit more structured and think about,
需要更加结构化的思维
if you can see like are you doing the right joint,
比如你在做右连接操作
should you put the bigger table on the left,
你要把更大的表格放在左边
and depending on the language, it's actually different.
语言不同 语法也不同
So, all those things are important,
这些事情都很重要
but I wouldn't say that something that I constantly keep in mind.
但我觉得这不值得去记
You have a question,
重要的是 你遇到一个问题
you try to get an answer,
然后尝试找到答案
but it does sound like maybe you are the person often optimizing those things.
听起来你好像是经常优化各种操作的人
It's not like some other team member that does that.
而不是团队的其他成员帮你做这件事
You have like data engineers who focus on that or
你是有数据工程师同时专门做这些 还是说
are those skills that you use as a data scientist in your regular job?
这些技能是你做数据科学家的日常工作的时候就用得到的？
Yeah, that's a good question.
问得好
Actually, I think all my knowledge are requiring a per need phases,
实际上我认为我的知识是根据需要现用现学的
but then because I do a lot of data engineering work.
不过 因为我做很多的数据工程工作
I learned a ton from people who are much better than I am,
我从那些比我优秀的人身上学到很多
and so over time I got better at this.
不断地我就越来越擅长这方面
So, what do you think falls into like maybe skills that you've
所以说 你觉得 你喜欢
picked up from data engineers that you're
从数据工程师身上学到的技能
really glad that you have now in you're day-to-day work?
从日常工作中学到这些很开心
Yeah. That's a great topic and a great question.
是的这是个很好的话题
Because I remember a few years ago,
我记得几年前
I was asking myself the same question because I wanted to learn more about
我问过我自己相同的问题 因为我当时想学习
data engineering and I was like searching online I couldn't find anything useful.
数据工程 我在上网搜索资料 但没有找到什么有用的信息
After joining Airbnb, I work a lot on their engineering project
在加入 Airbnb 后  我加入了他们的工程项目
with their engineers and there are a few things that I think are quite important.
和那些工程师一起工作 有几件事我认为很重要
So, the first thing would be to have a basic understanding of data modeling,
首先 要对数据建模有基本的认识
and so there are concepts such as how do you design a data warehouse,
这样才能对如何设计数据仓库有概念
data tables using star schema.
他们的数据表 (data table) 使用的是星型架构 star schema
So, the notion of a fact table or dimension table and how wide
所以 事实表 (fact table) 或维度表 (dimension table)
these two things are generally different behind how they can
为什么这两个概念是不同的？
be combined into building your data warehouse.
如何结合这两种方法来构建数据仓库？
Another concept is this notion of data backfilling.
另一个概念是数据回填 (data backfilling)
So, when you're building out a ETL pipeline,
你在搭建 ETL 管道的时候
most likely it's going to be automated job that will
应该是一个可自动化的成果
compute your metrics forward in time.
把你的指标计算出来
But then sometimes you want to be able to analyze historical data, historical trends.
但接下来有时候你想要能够分析历史数据 历史趋势
For those use cases there,
对于这种情况
you actually have to retroactively recompute metrics or history.
你实际上不得不重新计算指标和历史
So, the concept of data backfilling is also very,
所以数据回填就非常重要
very important, it's also very time-consuming.
这个工作也非常费时
So, knowing how to do proper backfilling and then monitor
所以 我认为 需要知道如何恰当地回填
the progress of your backfill jobs is something that I think very common,
并监控整个回填的进度很重要
very important but rarely taught in school.
但学校一般不教
The last thing I think is just working knowledge of building out ETL pipelines.
最后 搭建 ETL 管道方面 我从工作中学到的技巧
For that, it really depends.
就是 要分情况
At Airbnb, we use airflow which is an open source project that is very useful.
在 Airbnb 我们使用 airflow 这是一个很有用的开源项目
Just knowing how to not just write a ad hoc script but how do you
不应该仅仅能够写出临时的脚本应急
incorporate your queries into an ETL job that will be executed every day,
还应该将你的查询语句整合到你的 ETL 工作中 日常自动运行
I think that's a very valuable skill especially for data scientists.
我觉得这是一个对数据科学家来说非常有用的技能
It will help and unblock your work because you
它会让你的工作更顺畅
don't have to wait for data engineers to write
不需要等数据工程师们帮你写 ETL 占着数据
the ETL for you so they can consume the data, you can just do everything.
你一个人就能完成所有事情
For sure.
没错